<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elizabeth Orrico</title>
    <description>Personal Web site of Elizabeth Orrico.
</description>
    <link>http://www.elizabethorrico.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.elizabethorrico.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 17:28:00 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 17:28:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>First blog post</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;New coast, new website, new me! That’s right everyone, and I’ll be blogging about my hare-brained antics and hire-wire stunts right here, right now! So–blogging. Starting now. Go. Begin…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first, what will this blog be about? Travel? Cooking? Parenting? Since I’m an expert in all three, I guess there is only one available option, which is miscellany.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, this will be easy then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1.) &lt;strong&gt;Cupcakes.&lt;/strong&gt; Lately, I’ve become obsessed. In this way, I am a reverse hipster; I thought they were cool wayyy after everyone else had moved on. And I only like vanilla.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2.) &lt;strong&gt;Interesting things I’ve learned so far at work.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve really enjoyed the small bits of game theory I’ve been able to gather, not because the material really speaks to me, but because game theorists somehow, impossibly come up with the cutest names for everything they do. Seriously, every principle or story I come across has a more adorable name than the last did. Maybe this is just because I come from the cut-and-dry world of electrical engineering, where our best name is the Nyquist-Shannon sampling principle, but I have been dazzled by the creativity of the game theorists. Examples:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hidden_Markov_model&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hidden Markov Model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I put this one first because I doubt anyone will find it funny besides me. To be honest, I’m not even really sure why I think it’s funny. “What’s that, over there in the bushes?? Is it a Hidden Markov Model? Is it going to jump out and attack!?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Satisficing&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Satisficing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
That’s right, it means exactly what it sounds like: a portmanteau of “satisfying” and “sufficing”. Forget the fact that if something satisfies, it more than likely also suffices– these heady game theorists don’t think so! Thus “satisficing” was born.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_swan_theory&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Black Swan Theory&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This refers to the fact that as humans, we plan for the worst case situations, even when they are very rare and unlikely to ever occur–rare like a black swan. In fact, before the new world was discovered, Europeans believed there was no such thing as a black swan, so saying something was as rare as a black swan meant it was impossible. Thus, the theory is a nod to an old saying that originated from the Greek poet, Juvenal. I thought both the name and the theory behind it were quite poetic.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Keynesian_beauty_contest&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keynesian Beauty Contest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When I first read this in one set of online notes, I immediately perked up. “I’m beautiful,” I thought, with baited breath. “Maybe game theory is the place for me!” Much to my chagrin, the afore-mentioned is no beauty contest at all, but an extended metaphor for the stock market. Read about it on the Wikipedia page.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clearly, things are going a little slow for me now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3kcmwXUdDCE&quot;&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3kcmwXUdDCE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.elizabethorrico.com/2015/09/01/first-blog-post/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.elizabethorrico.com/2015/09/01/first-blog-post/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
